MATHEW COWDERY Software Developer

Dayton OH | 724.888.4077 | mcowdery@gmail.com | linkedIn.com/in/mathewcowdery| github.com/mcowdery

SUMMARY

Veteran with 5+ years of experience as a Cryptologic Analyst working with the Department of Defense (US Navy), 1+ year as a Software Developer, and 15+ years of overall professional experience.

Has a diverse background in the areas of business, software development, and cryptologic intelligence.

Demonstrates adaptability, leadership, professional demeanor, good interpersonal skills, and ability to excel in a high-paced environment.

TECHNICAL AND TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

Computational Thinking Fundamentals • Back-end Computer Programming/Object-Oriented Programming • Front-end Web Development • C# • .NET • REST API • TDD • Scrum • HTML • CSS • JavaScript • Git • React

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECT EXPERIENCE **GitHub:** https://mcowdery.github.io We Can Code IT

Planned, designed, and developed interactive applications in a collaborative, team-based, and independent setting, demonstrating the proficiency to earn a Software Development Certificate.

Class Of Your Choice

- Technologies/Processes used: C# (Console Development), Object-Oriented Programming (OOP).
- Designed and implemented a class of our choosing using Object-Oriented Programming principles and methodologies.

2023

 Enabled users to create and interact with a Pokemon-like creature using the console. Users are able to choose different species and

Virtual Pet

- Technologies/Processes used: C# (Console Development), Test-Driven Development (TDD), Object-Oriented Programming (OOP).
- Designed and implemented a Virtual Pet application in a 3-person team over 4 weeks.
- Enabled users to be recommended to movies based on 50+ data points; awarded most innovative project by (instructors).

Guided Tour Review Site

- Technologies/Processes used: C# (Web API Development), MVC, Entity Framework, SQL.
- Designed and implemented a reviews website for a guided tour company.
- Enabled users to dynamically generate new reviews for the company's guided tour products based on MVC architecture and utilizing full stack development, agile, OOP principles.

EDUCATION

We Can Code IT, Columbus, OH 2023

Certificate of Software Development

Geneva College, Beaver Falls, PA 2010 - 2013

B. S. Computer Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

Entrepreneur (Self-employed)

Airbnb Business Owner & Host, Dayton OH

August 2022-Present

 Received business development and entrepreneurship experience while starting and managing a successful Airbnb business. Hosted over 240+ guests with an average review score of 4.98 out of 5 stars. (https://www.airbnb.ca/users/show/393992041)

Booz Allen Hamilton

Software Developer/Cryptologic Analyst, Ft. Meade, MD

August 2021-August 2022

• Worked and trained on various classified projects. Unclassified tools used included Python, Git, GitLab, Docker, AWS, and Jupyter Notebook.

U.S. Navy,

CTR2 (E-5), Wahiawa, HI

May 2016–May 2020

- Lead Proforma Analyst (August 2017—May 2020): Provided crucial situational awareness and Indications and Warnings to forward-deployed naval forces in the PACOM Area of Responsibility (AOR), preparing and disseminating over 3,000 high priority PROFORMA products to combatant commanders across the AOR.
- Area Analyst (March 2019–May 2020): Constructed and delivered 18 daily intelligence briefs to senior leadership with CTF 1070. Responsible for editing and releasing 21 theater assessments to provide situational awareness and posturing of AOR to 3rd, 5th, and 7th fleets, Pacific Command, deployed to US assets, and FVEY partners.
- Chief of Naval Operations Special Missions Operator (September 2017–May 2020): Drafted and released 585 time-critical reports, and reviewed over 660 messages in support of Special Access CNO Directed missions. Improving situational awareness to Pacific Fleet combatants with threat warning and actionable intelligence, resulting in successful operation with zero incidents reported for the program.
- Department Training Petty Officer (August 2017–February2020): Responsible for tracking and managing over 250 Sailor's General Military Trainings (GMT's), leading to 100% accountability for all personnel

Securitas Security Services,

Security Officer, Pittsburgh, PA

June 2008-May 2016

• Supervised site personnel as site supervisor. Managed over a dozen personnel, ensuring 100% manning of all posts.